LAURA BERMUDEZ GARCIA

Kirkland, WA 98034 | Phone: 2069729255 | Email: laurabermudezg@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/laura-bermudez-garcia/ | Github: https://github.com/lbeagleeyes |

Portfolio: https://lbeagleeyes.github.io/Portfolio-LauraBermudez/

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 10 years of experience, recently graduated from a Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp at the University of Washington, passionate about user-centered design, able to work as a liaison between technical and non-technical teams due to excellent communication skills and experience gathering requirements.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

C/C++, C#.Net, SQL, HTML, CSS, JS, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, React

WORK EXPERIENCE

Stay home mom

08/2014 - present

• Raise 6 children while keeping up to date with technology through UW continuing education.

Software Engineer / Systems Analyst Intel Corporation

08/2011 - 09/2014

San Jose, Costa Rica

- .Net C# developer for a data analysis tool that logs tens of thousands of data in more than 200 servers across continents with a user interface that enables data visualization for monitoring and analysis
- .Net C# (HTML5, MVC, Javascript, JQuery) developer for fab construction project that consolidates 3 applications in one to improve customer's productivity and user experience.
- As a systems analyst, gathered requirements, developed mock-ups, and created user stories to improve communication between customers and developers while using Agile Methodologies and Kanban
- Key Accomplishments: Winner of a Division Recognition Award (DRA)

Software Developer Desert Development Company

12/2009 - 07/2011

San Jose. Costa Rica

- C++ software developer for a new games suite making good use of design patterns and SCRUM.
- Developed frameworks in C++ for server and in Actionscript 3.0 for flash client that significantly increased development productivity.

Software Engineer Western Union

04/2007 - 02/2010

San Jose, Costa Rica

- Coordinator between teams to deliver new releases worldwide, gathering requirements from different regions to design and develop new features using C/C++ with MFC, ASP and SQL Server technologies for core business money transfer software distribution system.
- *Key Accomplishments:* Winner of a quarterly award for excellent teamwork during a national Money Transfer software roll out for US and Canada.

Software Engineer Alian Technology

02/2006- 03/2007

San Jose, Costa Rica

- Improved company's productivity through requirements gathering and development of new features for a C++/MFC 3D graphics application used to model orthodontic treatments.
- Improved the company's knowledge management by developing web applications in PHP, JavaScript and MySql.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp: University of Washington, Seattle, WA. 2019

Software Product Management Certificate: University of Washington, Bellevue, WA. 2017-2018

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science: University of Costa Rica, San Jose, Costa Rica. 2004